Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians (CIRL) Records 5171
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians (CIRL) Records
1945-2008
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians (CIRL)
5171
10.5 cubic feet
10.5 linear ft.
Photographs, thesauri.
Administrative records consist of memoranda, correspondence, minutes and reports pertaining to the Committee's annual conferences (1947-1982) and memoranda, notes and letters concerning classification systems, retention policies, subject headings, research and education, exhibits, reference services and membership.
3336785
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 27, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 01, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The Committee serves as a forum for an exchange of ideas and information, and engages in cooperative projects designed to improve the usefulness of materials in the industrial and labor relations field.
Scope and Contents
Administrative records consist of memoranda, correspondence, minutes and reports pertaining to the Committee's annual conferences (1947-1982) and memoranda, notes and letters concerning classification systems, retention policies, subject headings, research and education, exhibits, reference services and membership.
Also catalog cards, photographs of meetings, exhibit materials, chronologies of the Committee (1947-1972), newsletters (1968-1978), directories of industrial relations programs in North America (1961-1972), and copies of INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS THESES AND DISSERTATIONS: A COMPILATION SPONSORED BY THE COMMITTEE OF UNIVERSITY INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS LIBRARIANS (1951-1972). Includes tape recordings of 1971 and 1975 meetings.
Additionally, documentation of the Subject Headings Subcommittee's projects to establish a thesaurus of standardized industrial and labor relations subject terms. Include copies and revisions of A STANDARDIZED LIST OF SUBJECT HEADINGS IN INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS (1963-1968), and memoranda, reports, notes and correspondence of Subcommittee members concerning subject terms and the agenda of meetings (1949-1968).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5171 P: Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians (CIRL) 38th Annual Conference Photographs 6359: Melba Kibildis CIRL Annual Meeting Materials 6359 P: Maria Cataflio CIRL Photographs
Cataloging of special collections in libraries; Industrial relations -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States; Special librarians -- Congresses; Librarians.; Industrial relations libraries; Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians
3336785
- US Navy: Air Rework Facility (Box 15, Folder 1)
- US Navy: Air Station Oceana (Box 15, Folder 2)
- US Navy: Exchange (Box 15.1, Folder 3)
- US Navy: Norfolk Shipyard [folder 1 of 6] (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Agenda, 1947; Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    University of Chicago, June 8th & 9th
    Format: Text.
  - Item 2: Report to the Conference of Industrial Relations Directors on Special Problems Confronting the Industrial Relations Librarian, 1947; Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Report on Second Annual CIRL in Washington, D.C., June 7 and 8, 1948, Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Minutes, 1948; Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
    Minutes for the 2nd Annual CIRL in Washington DC on June 7 and 8, 1948
  - Item 5: Report on Third Annual CIRL in Los Angeles, California, June 12, 1949, Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 6: Report of the Fourth Annual CIRL at Princeton University, June 16 and 17, 1950, Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 7: Report of Fifth Annual CIRL at the University of Minnesota, June 16 and 17, 1951, Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 8: Minutes of the Sixth Annual CIRL at Princeton University, May 24 and 25, 1952, Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
  - Item 9: Proceeding of the Seventh Annual CIRL in Toronto, Canada, June 26 and 27, 1953, Text (Box 15.1, Folder 4)
- US Navy: Norfolk Shipyard [folder 2 of 6], Text (Box 15.1, Folder 5)
- US Navy: Norfolk Shipyard [folder 3 of 6], Text (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: 17th Annual CIRL Conference, 1963; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    May 31 - June 1 in Ithaca, NY
    Format: Program.
  - Item 2: 19th Annual CIRL Conference, 1965; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    June 4 and 5 in Princeton, NJ
  - Item 3: 20th Annual CIRL Meeting, 1966; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    May 27 and 28 in Minneapolis, MN
  - Item 4: 21st Annual CIRL Conference, 1967; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    May 25 - 27 in Princeton, NJ
  - Item 5: 21st Annual Meeting Minutes, 1967; Text (Box 15, Folder 6)
    A memo is attached to the front saying the minutes have been revised, with the minutes following the memo
  - Item 6: 22nd Annual CIRL Conference, 1968; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    May 31 and June 1 in Pasadena, CA
  - Item 7: 23rd Annual CIRL Conference, 1969; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    June 6 and 7 in Montreal, Canada
  - Item 8: 24th Annual CIRL Conference, 1970; Program (Box 15, Folder 6)
    June 5 and 6 in Ann Arbor, MI
- US Navy: Norfolk Shipyard [folder 4 of 6], Program (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: 25th Anniversary CIRL Conference, 1971; Program (Box 15, Folder 7)
    May 28 and 29 at Cornell University in Ithaca, NY
  - Item 2: 26th Annual CIRL Conference, 1972; Program (Box 15, Folder 7)
    June 9 and 10 at MIT
  - Item 3: 27th Annual CIRL Conference, 1973; Program (Box 15, Folder 7)
    May 31 and June 1 in Chicago, IL
- US Navy: Norfolk Shipyard [folder 5 of 6], Program (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: 28th Annual CIRL Conference, 1974; Program (Box 15, Folder 8)
    June 6 and 7 at Michigan State University
  - Item 2: 29th Annual CIRL Conference, 1975; Program (Box 15, Folder 8)
    June 19 and 20 in Ottawa, Canada
  - Item 3: 30th Annual CIRL Conference, 1976; Program (Box 15, Folder 8)
    May 6 and 7 in Princeton, NJ
  - Item 4: 31st Annual CIRL Conference, 1977; Program (Box 15, Folder 8)
    June 1 - 3 in Urbana, IL
  - Item 5: 32nd Annual CIRL Conference Partial Summary Proceedings, 1978; Program (Box 15, Folder 8)
    held at MIT
- US Navy: Norfolk Shipyard [folder 6 of 6], Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: 33rd Annual CIRL Conference, 1979; Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
    May 30 and June 1 in Toronto
  - Item 2: 34th Annual CIRL Conference, 1980; Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
    June 4 - 6 in Washington, D.C.
  - Item 3: 35th Annual CIRL Conference Agenda, 1981; Text (Box 15, Folder 9)
    May 27 - 29 at Cornell
  - Item 4: 35th Annual CIRL Conference, 1981; Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
    held May 27 -29 at Cornell
  - Item 5: 36th Annual CIRL Conference, 1982; Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
    June 10 - 11 in Ann Arbor, MI (three copies)
  - Item 6: 40th Annual CIRL Conference, 1986; Program (Box 15, Folder 9)
    April 30 - May 2 in Detroit, MI
- US Navy: Ordinance Station, Program (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: 41st Annual CIRL Conference, 1987; Program (Box 15, Folder 10)
    April 29 in Boston, MA
  - Item 2: 44th Annual CIRL Conference, 1990; Program (Box 15, Folder 10)
    May 23 - 25 in Ithaca, NY
  - Item 3: 47th Annual CIRL Conference, 1993; Program (Box 15, Folder 10)
    May 6 - 8 in Washington, D.C.
  - Item 4: 46th Annual CIRL Conference, 1992; Program (Box 15, Folder 10)
    May 13 - 15 at Rutgers University
  - Item 5: 48th Annual CIRL Conference, 1994; Program (Box 15, Folder 10)
    May 12 - 14 at Michigan State University
- US Social Security Admin. [folder 1 of 3], Program (Box 15, Folder 15)
- US Small Business Admin., Program (Box 15, Folder 14)
- US Patent & Trademark Office [folder 2 of 2], Program (Box 15, Folder 13)
- US Park Police, Program (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Submitted at Seventeen Universities, 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    July 1, 1949 through June 30, 1950
  - Item 2: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at Thirty-one Universities, 1954-1955 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    July 1, 1954 - June 30, 1955
  - Item 3: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at Thirty-eight Universities, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    July 1, 1955 - June 30, 1956
  - Item 4: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at Thirty-six Universities, 1956-1957 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    July 1, 1956 - June 30, 1957
  - Item 5: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at Thirty-eight Universities, 1957-1958 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    July 1, 1957 - June 30, 1958
- US Patent & Trademark Office [folder 1 of 2], Text (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at 40 Universities, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    July 1958 - December 1959
  - Item 2: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at 36 Universities, 1960-1963 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at 27 Universities, 1970; Text (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Item 4: Industrial Relations Theses and Dissertations Accepted at 26 Universities, 1972; Text (Box 15, Folder 12)
- US Social Security Admin. [folder 2 of 3], Text (Box 15, Folder 16)
- US Social Security Admin. [folder 3 of 3], Text (Box 15, Folder 17)
- US Veteran's Admin. Medical Center, Text (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Vermont Northern RR Co., Text (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Virginia-Pilot Ledger Star, Text (Box 15, Folder 20)
- WDCA-TV, Text (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Washington Gas and Light Co. [folder 1 of 4], Text (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Washington Gas and Light Co. [folder 2 of 4], Text (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Washington Gas and Light Co. [folder 3 of 4], Text (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Washington Gas and Light Co. [folder 4 of 4], Text (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Westinghouse Broadcasting Company, WJZ-TV [folder 1 of 2], Text (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Westinghouse Broadcasting Company, WJZ-TV [folder 2 of 2], Text (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Washington-Baltimore Newspaper Guild, Text (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Washington County Board of Education, Text (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Washington Hospital Center [folder 1 of 5], Text (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Washington Hospital Center [folder 2 of 5], Text (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Washington Hospital Center [folder 3 of 5], Text (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Washington Hospital Center [folder 4 of 5], Text (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Washington Hospital Center [folder 5 of 5], Text (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Washington Metropolitan Transit Authority [folder 1 of 2], Text (Box 16, Folder 12)
- Washington Metropolitan Transit Authority [folder 2 of 2], Text (Box 16, Folder 13)
- W.D. Byron and Sons, Inc., Text (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Western Pacific RR Co. [folder 1 of 4], Text (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Western Pacific RR Co. [folder 2 of 4], Text (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Western Pacific RR Co. [folder 3 of 4], Text (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Western Pacific RR Co. [folder 4 of 4], Text (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Western Pennsylvania Water Co., Text (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Westinghouse Electric Corp., Text (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Winner Distributing Company, Text (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Western Railroad Awards, Text (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Nation Railroad Adjustment Board, Fourth Division Awards [folder 1 of 2], Text (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Nation Railroad Adjustment Board, Fourth Division Awards [folder 2 of 2], Text (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Docket #2, Text (Box 17, Folder 6)
- E.I. DuPont de Nemours and Company Vol. I, Text (Box 17, Folder 7)
- E.I. DuPont de Nemours and Company Vol. I [cont.], Text (Box 17, Folder 8)
- E.I. DuPont de Nemours and Company Vol. II, Text (Box 17, Folder 9)
- CUIRL, MIT, 1972; Text (Box 12, Folder 5)
- CUIRL, Chicago, 1973; Text (Box 12, Folder 6)
- CUIRL, Correspondence, 1973; Text (Box 12, Folder 7)
- CUIRL, Planning, 1973; Text (Box 12, Folder 8)
- CUIRL, Centralized Information Service, Text (Box 12, Folder 9)
- CUIRL, Committee Receipts, Text (Box 12, Folder 10)
- CUIRL, Exchange Bibliography Consolidation, Text (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Librarian Conferences, Text (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Report to Librarians on IRC Conference Report to Director's on IRC Conference, Text (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Librarian's Conference, 1949; Text (Box 12, Folder 14)
  June
- Chronology, 1946-1965 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- CUIRL Correspondence, Union List, Text (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Theses, Text (Box 12, Folder 17)
- CUIRL, Index to Labor Periodicals, Text (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Labor Union Archives, Text (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Union Depository, Text (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Weeding Survey, 1958; Text (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Directory of Industrial Relations Degree Programs Offered at Colleges and Universities in the US and Canada, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Results of the Statistical Survey of I & L R Libraries, 1972; Text (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous, Text (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous, Text (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous, Text (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous, Text (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous, Text (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous, Text (Box 13, Folder 8)
- CUIRL, Project: Manual of biblio. and index., 1958; Text (Box 14, Folder 1)
- CUIRL, Miscellaneous Papers, 1948-1955 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- CUIRL, Questionnaire to Ind. Rel. groups, 1955-1956 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Industrial Relations Departments, 1956; Text (Box 14, Folder 4)
  original tables and revision of tables
- CUIRL Exchange Agreement, 1978; Text (Box 14, Folder 5)
- CUIRL, Project: Exchange Bibliographies, Text (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Photos, Text (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Photos, Text (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Photos, Text (Box 14, Folder 9)
- CIRL, Text (Box 14, Folder 10)
  mostly more photos in this folder
- Photos, Text (Box 14, Folder 11)
- CIRL 1978 - 1982 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- CIRL, 1984, Text (Box 16, Folder 2)
- CIRL 38th Annual Meeting Correspondence, 1984; Text (Box 16, Folder 3)
- CIRL 38th Annual Meeting Invitations, 1984; Text (Box 16, Folder 4)
- CIRL 38th Annual Meeting Flyers, 1984; Text (Box 16, Folder 5)
- CIRL 38th Annual Meeting Notes, 1984; Text (Box 16, Folder 6)
- CIRL 38th Annual Meeting, RSVPs, 1984; Text (Box 16, Folder 7)
  Last names Aroeste - Koepp
- CIRL 38th Annual Meeting, RSVPs, 1984; Text (Box 16, Folder 8)
  Last names Law - Young
- CIRL, 1986, Text (Box 16, Folder 9)
- CIRL, 1987, Text (Box 16, Folder 10)
- CIRL, 1989, Text (Box 16, Folder 11)
- CIRL, 1990, Text (Box 16, Folder 12)
- CIRL, 1991, Text (Box 16, Folder 13)
- CIRL, 1992, Text (Box 16, Folder 14)
- CIRL, 1993, Text (Box 16, Folder 15)
- CIRL, 1995, Text (Box 16, Folder 16)
- CIRL, 1996, Text (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Union Differences for Library Workers, 2006; Text (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Fact Sheet 2008. Library Workers: Facts and Figures, Text (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Fact Sheet 2008. Professional Women: Vital Statistics, Text (Box 16, Folder 20)
- AFL-CIO/ALA. Library Service to Labor Groups, RUSA, 2008; Text (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Subject Index to the Reference Collection on Industrial Relations, 1946; Text (Box 17, Folder 1)
- CUIRL Directory, 1995; Text (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Industrial Relations Library, Statement of Function Survey, 1972; Text (Box 17, Folder 3)
- IRIS and Feasibility Study, 1967-1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- ISIS, 1977; Text (Box 17, Folder 5)
- CUIRL - Cooperative Exchange Agreements, 1976-1978 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Report on Exchange Bibliographies, 1977; Text (Box 17, Folder 7)
- CUIRL - Exchange Bibliographies, 1995; Text (Box 17, Folder 8)
  years vary over decades; most recent is 1995
- CUIRL - History, 1946-1965 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- CIRL Newsletter, 1995; Text (Box 17, Folder 10)
- CIRL 58th Annual Conference, 2004; Text (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Held in Berkeley, CA
- CIRL 2003, Text (Box 17, Folder 12)
- CIRL 2002 Conference, Text (Box 17, Folder 13)
  annual conference info
- CIRL 2001 Conference, Text (Box 17, Folder 14)
  info and pamphlets on the 2001 annual conference
- CIRL 2000 Conference, Text (Box 17, Folder 15)
- CIRL 1999 Conference, Text (Box 17, Folder 16)
  info on the 1999 CIRL conference
- CIRL 1998, Text (Box 17, Folder 17)
- CIRL 1998 Spring Meeting, Text (Box 17, Folder 18)
  program/folder of info from the 1998 spring meeting at the Carlson School
- CIRL 1997, Text (Box 17, Folder 19)
- CIRL 1996, Text (Box 17, Folder 20)
- CIRL 1995, Text (Box 17, Folder 21)
- CIRL 1994, Text (Box 17, Folder 22)
- CIRL 1993, Text (Box 17, Folder 23)
- CIRL 1992, Text (Box 17, Folder 24)
- CIRL 1991, Text (Box 17, Folder 25)
- CIRL 1990, Text (Box 17, Folder 26)
- CIRL 1988, Text (Box 17, Folder 27)
- CIRL 1987, Text (Box 17, Folder 28)
- CIRL 1986, Text (Box 17, Folder 29)
- CIRL 1985, Text (Box 17, Folder 30)
- CIRL 1984, Text (Box 17, Folder 31)
- CIRL 1983, Text (Box 17, Folder 32)
- CIRL 1982, Text (Box 17, Folder 33)
- CIRL 1981, Text (Box 17, Folder 34)
- CUIRL 1980, Text (Box 17, Folder 35)
- CIRL 1979, Text (Box 17, Folder 36)
- CUIRL 1978, Text (Box 17, Folder 37)
- CUIRL 1977, Text (Box 17, Folder 38)
- Thesaurus Project, 1974-1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Years vary, majority of papers are from the 70's
- Thesaurus (2), 1974-1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Again, majority of papers in the folder are from the 1970's, though years vary
- Blank Concept Analysis Sheets, Text (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Blank Abstract Forms, Text (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Kuehn Report, 1975; Text (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Labor Issues Caucus, 2004; Text (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Labor Issues Caucus 1998 Meeting, Text (Box 18, Folder 7)
- CIRL 1983, Text (Box 19, Folder 1)
  1983 Annual Conference for CIRL
- Standard List of Subject Headings - CUIRL, Advertisement for 2nd edition, 1963; Text (Box 19, Folder 2)
- CUIRL Draft Agenda for 19th Annual Meeting, 1965; Text (Box 19, Folder 3)
- CIRL - Cooperative Exchange Project, 1971; Text (Box 19, Folder 4)
- CIRL- Committee of Industrial Relations Librarians, 2001; Text (Box 19, Folder 5)
- CUIRL Meeting - 1976, Text (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Collection development, Text (Box 19, Folder 7)
  no year listed
- CUIRL, Text (Box 19, Folder 8)
- CUIRL, Text (Box 19, Folder 9)
  miscellaneous papers
- CIRL Homepage, Text (Box 19, Folder 10)
- CIRL - Newsletter, Text (Box 19, Folder 11)
- CIRL Conference, 1997; Text (Box 19, Folder 12)
  April 17 - 19
- CIRL Conference Mailing - Preliminary Program, Text (Box 19, Folder 13)
- CIRL Conference Final Mailing, Text (Box 19, Folder 14)
- CIRL Conference Responses, Text (Box 19, Folder 15)
- CIRL Conference Banquet, Text (Box 19, Folder 16)
- CIRL Agenda - Working Documents, Text (Box 19, Folder 17)
- CIRL Website, Text (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Images digitized from the collection., Text (Box 20)